A Guide to the Rockefeller University Press, Graphic Services, Photographs, Oversized Prints FA1156
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University Press, Graphic Services, Photographs, Oversized Prints
1906-1971
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University Press
Rockefeller University
FA1156
9.2 Cubic Feet 5 flat boxes and 2 packages.
Arrangement
Original order.
Scope and Contents
Contains a variety of large size portraits, exterior and interior buildings shots, and site views. Dimensions for some items are individually documented.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
File Plan
Former Classification: I 529
- Portraits - Frederick T. Gates (Box 1)
- Portraits - Simon Flexner (Box 1)
- Portraits - Louis Pasteur (Box 1)
- Portraits - Frederick T. Gates (Box 1)
- Portraits - John D. Rockefeller, 1911 (Box 1)
- Portraits - Enrique E. Ecker - Drawing, 1957, 1958 (Box 1)
- Portraits - Tom Horton Retirement Dinner (Box 1)
- Portraits - Herbert S. Gasser (Box 1)
- Portraits - Rudolf Vurchow (Box 1)
- Portraits - Emil Fischer (Box 1)
- Portraits - Max Joseph von Pettenkofer (Box 1)
- Portraits - Theophil Mitchell Prudden (Box 1)
- Portraits - Dr. Koch (Box 1)
- Portraits - Alexis Carrel, 1920 April 20 (Box 2)
- Group Portraits - Board of Scientific Directors, 1951 (Box 2)
- Group Portraits - Board of Scientific Directors, 1940 (Box 2)
- Group Portraits - Board of Scientific Directors, 1931-1938 (Box 2)
- Portraits - T. H. Morgan, 1971 May 25 (Box 2)
- Portraits - Christian Archibald Herter (Box 3)
- Portraits - Howard B. Cross, 1922 Volunteer (Box 3)
- Portraits - First Hospital Staff (Box 3)
- Portraits - Marie Curie, 1929 November 8 (Box 3)
- Poatraits - Opie and others (Box 3)
- Portraits - John D. Rockefeller, Jr, 1927 (Box 3)
- Portraits - John Hunter (Box 3)
- Portraits - Peyton Rous, 1914 (Box 3)
- Portraits - Jerome Davis Greene, First Institute Manager, 1916 (Box 3)
- Buildings, Site - Glacial markings, excavations for Hospital, Rockefeller University, 1908; Glossy print, 6x8 (Box 4)
- Buildings, Site - Photograph of excavation for new laboratory and Animal Building, 1928 September 4; mounted glossy print, 10.5x21 (Folder 1)
- Buildings, Site - Picture of first laboratory of the Rockefeller Institute at 127 E. 50th St, New York City from Oct. 15, 1904 to May 11, 1906, when the location was occupied. From reverse - NE Corner Lexington and 50th, 1904-1906; 2 identical mounted print, 15x17 (Box 4)
- Buildings, Site - Drawing - Photos of Coolidge Design - Middle Laboratory and Animal House, print, 10x14 (Box 4)
- Buildings, Site - Photos of Coolidge Design - from East River showing Middle Laboratory, Animal House, Power House, 2 identical print, 6x14 (Box 4)
- Buildings, Site - Recreational space - likely 63rd street to 68th street, shows use of land down to Avenue A (York Ave.), c. 1932; mounted print, 15x19 (Box 4)
- Buildings, Site - Rockefeller Institute from medical Research - showing original Power House and Animal House, 1906; glossy print, 9x11 (Box 4)
- Buildings, Site - Miniature of Princeton property, With compliments of J. Howard Brown, Rockefeller Institute, Princeton, NJ, 1920 June; Photo detached from board, 6.5x15 (Box 4)
- Buildings, Site - View from the East River, 59th St. bridge to 73rd St., signed E. G. Stillman, 1943; Mounted print, 11x36 (Box 4)
- Buildings, Site - Thomas Airviews aerial photo of the Institute and groups from 63rd-68th, contains various reproduction instructions on reverse mount, c. 1951; Mounted glossy print, 11x14 (Box 4)
- Buildings, Site - Hospital - From the River, sepia, area near shed gray, Mounted print, 12x16 (Box 4)
- Buildings, Site - Hospital - From the River except gray area replaced with G. Corps sign, rocks extended to cover ladder, Glossy print, 12x16 (Box 4)
- Buildings, Site - Hospital - Isolation Building and Main Building, Mounted print, 12x16 (Box 4)
- Buildings, Site - Coolidge, Shepley, Bulfinch and Abbott - Colored drawing of remodeled Rigley House, Princeton, 1927 April 7; colored drawing, mounted, 14x24 (Folder 1)
- Buildings, Site - Four prints mounted together, forming a panorama showing from a construction site to a bridge, 4 mounted glossy prints, 14x36 (Box 4)
- Buildings, Site - Aerial photos, 2 mounted prints and 1 copy print (Folder 1)
- Buildings, Site - Aerial photograph of Princeton grounds, Curtiss Wright Flying Service, 1 print, 16x24 (Folder 1)
- Buildings, Site - View RIMR from Avenue A - shows clearly Central Laboratory, Middle Laboratory and Animal House, Isolation Pavillion, Hospital, Power House, signed Irving Underhill, NY, c. 1917; 1 mounted print, 16x20 (Box 4)
- Buildings, Site - Construction of base hospital, 1917; 9 prints, 11x14 (Box 5)
- Portaits - Two unused group photographs (Lederberg and Nobelists) taken by photographer for Sept. 1982 article in Town and Country. Copy of article stored with photos, 1982 September; 2 prints, plus paper documentation, 11x14 (Box 5)
- Portraits - RIMR Maintenance Staff, 1908; 1 glossy print, mounted, 11x20 (Box 5)
- Buildings, Site - Founder's Hall Entrance, 1 glossy print, 10x14 (Box 5)
- Buildings, Site - Campus Views, 1930s; 1 print, 11x14 (Box 5)
- Portraits - Diamond Jubilee of Tom Hoton from Rockefeller Insitute Employees, Sokol Hall, 1938 March 16; 1 print in two parts, 1 sheet of documentation (Box 5)
- Buildings, Site - Tower Building Construction, 1967-1969; 10 bound pages containing color prints (Box 5)
- Buildings, Site - Hospital Exterior, 1955; 1 print, 11x14 (Box 5)
- Buildings, Site - Hospital, 1955; 1 print, 11x14 (Box 5)
- From P.I., Sci Ed. Program Pictures - RU Press, 1930 June 1983; Assorted photos, bound (Box 5)
- Buildings, Site - Aerial view of campus at night - from NY Hospital, 1 print, 11x14 (Box 5)
- Pat Levene's Lab, 201-02 Founder's - after explosion, Neg 1818, 1931 January; 1 print, 11x14 (Box 5)
- Pat Levene's Lab after explosion in 1913, Copy Neg A-27855, 1931 January; 1 print, 11x14 (Box 5)
- Group at Dr. Seitz installation, in academic regalia (Unidentified, George Palade, Unidentified, Normal Stoll, Detlev W. Bronk, Father Hesburgh, Not Visible, David Rockefeller), 1968 October 8; 1 print, and paper documentation, 9.5x14 (Box 5)
- RU Board of Trustees Executive Committee Meeting, photo used in 1972-1973 RU Report of the President, p.8., c. 1971; 1 print, 10x14 (Box 5)
- Welch Hall - Dining Room, in - Kobler, John The Rockefeller University Story 1970, RU Press (in vault) Some IDs - Floyd Ratliff, Lyman C. Craig, Clarence Connolly, 1 print and ID sheet, 9x14 (Box 5)
- CASPARY interior - photo included in a print advertisement, 1 print advertisement, 11x16 (Box 5)
- Hospital, 1914; 1 print, 12x16 (Box 5)
- Pasteur, Louis painted by A. Edelfelt in 1885, package (Box 6)
  Scope and Contents note
  Photogravure published in New York by M. Knoedler in 1886 Signed: L. Pasteur
- Welch, William Henry dry-point portrait by Alfred Hutty, package (Box 7)
  Presented to Simon Flexner, committee in charge of celebration of William Henry Welch 80th birthday, 8 April 1930 Presented to RIMR by the Milbank Fund Signed by Alfred Hutty and signed by William Henry Welch.